<form script="es_use_case.js" stylesheet="/style/app.css">
  <label>UBA Use Case</label>
  <fieldset submitButton="false"></fieldset>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>About Splunk User Behavior Analytics</h2>
        <div style="float:left; width:10%">
          <br/>
                   <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/land_images/UBA_Use_Case.png"/>
 
        </div>
        <div style="float:right; width:89%">
	<p></p>
        <p>You're exploring an example that is best accomplished with <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/products/premium-solutions/user-behavior-analytics.html" target="_blank">Splunk's User Behavior Analytics (UBA).</a>
          </p>
        <p>UBA is Splunk's security product dedicated to finding anomalies and threats surrounding user, application, and device behavior, using unsupervised machine learning. UBA discovers anomalies and stitches them together into threats, and also provides risk scoring so that analysts can quickly understand which threats to investigate first. A rich visual environment allows analysts and threat hunters to pivot through and investigate the anomalous behavior. Other important UBA features include:</p>
        <li>A Big Data foundation including Hadoop, Spark, and GrqphDB to support enterprise-level environments;</li>
        <li>Multi-dimensional behavior baselining to identify true outliers;</li>
        <li>Custom threat generation, and an API to allow your data scientists to create their own models;</li>
        <li>Support for user monitoring and on-the-fly watch lists; and</li>
        <li>Integrates with <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/products/premium-solutions/splunk-enterprise-security.html" target="_blank">Splunk ES</a> to drill further into the data from user behavior threats and anomalies.</li>
        <br/>
        </div>
        </html>
      <html>
        <p>
          <b>The Security Examples marked as <span style="float:none; font-weight: normal;" class="grayAppButton">Try UBA</span>within Security Essentials are "out-of-the-box" anomaly detections within UBA, as shown in the screencaps that you can select below. Find out more about Splunk UBA <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/products/premium-solutions/user-behavior-analytics.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</b>
        </p>
        </html>
    </panel>
    <panel depends="$gotusecase$"><html><h2>Your Use Case</h2><div id="usecasecontent"></div></html></panel>
  </row>
  <row><panel depends="$gotusecasedetails$"><html><h2>Details for your Use Case</h2><div id="usecasedetail"></div></html></panel>
  </row>
  <row><panel depends="$gotusecasescreenshots$"><html><h2>Screenshots for your Use Case</h2><div id="usecasescreenshots"></div></html></panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <input type="link" token="needed">
        <label>Select a Security Journey Stage for an Example Screenshot</label>
        <choice value="stage4">Enrichment</choice>
        <choice value="stage6">Advanced</choice>
        <default>stage4</default>
        <change>
          <condition value="stage4">
            <set token="showstage4">true</set>
            <unset token="showstage1"></unset>
            <unset token="showstage3"></unset>
            <unset token="showstage2"></unset>
            <unset token="showstage6"></unset>
          </condition>
          <condition value="stage6">
            <set token="showstage6">true</set>
            <unset token="showstage1"></unset>
            <unset token="showstage3"></unset>
            <unset token="showstage4"></unset>
            <unset token="showstage2"></unset>
          </condition>
        </change>
      </input>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html depends="$showstage4$">
        <h2>Example Stage 4 UBA Anomaly:</h2><h3><i>Multiple Logins</i>
        </h3>
        <br/>
        <div style="float:left; width:79%">
                   <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/land_images/stage4_uba.png"/>
        </div>
      </html>
      <html depends="$showstage6$">
        <h2>Example Stage 6 UBA Anomaly:</h2><h3><i>Suspicious Domain Communication</i>
        </h3>
        <br/>
        <div style="float:left; width:79%">
                   <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/land_images/stage6_uba.png"/>
        </div>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel depends="$Superman$">
      <html>
        <h3>Geographically Improbable Accesses (Superman Problem)</h3>
        <p>The superman problem is one of the first use cases most UEBA solutions take on -- detecting account compromise by looking for sequential logins from distant parts of the world, where it is in improbable someone might travel (such as a login from North Korea 5 minutes or 5 seconds after a login San Francisco).</p>
        <p>This use case is so common, that you can actually solve it in several places within Splunk. It is provided as a native anomaly in Splunk UBA, you can download a community supported app called <a href="https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/3232/">SA-geodistance</a>. However, if you don't have UBA deployed yet, and you don't want to try to configure a community supported app to work for you, Splunk ES has this out of the box! Under Security Intelligence -&gt; User Intelligence -&gt; Access Anomalies, you can find a series of report of use, including the Geographically Improbable Accesses report. To automatically be alerted, or automatically integrate this into your Anomaly Aggregation solution of choice (Splunk UBA, ES Risk, etc.), ES also has a correlation rule out of the box to do this detection. </p>
        <h3>Screenshot(s)</h3>
        <div style="float:left; width:49%">
          <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/es_images/es_superman.png"/>
        </div>
        <div style="float:right; width:49%">
          <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/es_images/es_ir_superman.png"/>
        </div>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel depends="$ListeningPort$">
      <html>
        <h3>Anomalous New Listening Port</h3>
        <p>Unusual new listening ports is a sign of potential malware persistence in your environment. Building out this search, with the potential cardinality of every unique port on every system in your environment can be a trial. Fortunately, Splunk ES ships this search out of the box!</p>

        <p>Just as with many anomalies, it may be benign -- the installation of some new software that opens new listening ports -- so it is important to correlate this event with other anomalous events in your environment though an aggregation layer, such as Splunk UBA (or as a starting point, Splunk ES's Risk Framework). </p>
        <h3>Screenshot(s)</h3>
        <div style="float:left; width:49%">
          <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/es_images/es_anomalous_listening_port.png"/>
        </div>
        <div style="float:right; width:49%">
          <img style="border: gray 1px solid;" src="/static/app/Splunk_Security_Essentials/images/es_images/es_ir_anomalous_listening_port.png"/>
        </div>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</form>